已经挺晚的了
It's pretty late.
不过 我还来得及再做几次
You think I've got time to run some more simulations
冷却系统的模拟吗?
on the cooling system?
来得及 我还在纠结
Sure, I'm still figuring out
热声扩张器呢
the thermo-acoustic expander.
你们先忙着吧
Oh, while you do that
我需要让脑脊液
I am going to pump cerebral spinal fluid
滋润大脑里的每一个细胞 清除这一天飞速运转所产生的
through my brain cells to remove the metabolic by-products
新陈代谢副产物
of the day's thoughts.
什么鬼?
What?
这叫睡眠 我该睡觉了
It's called sleep and it's my bedtime.
晚安 么么哒
Nighty-night, y'all.
喂 你不许走
Hey, hey, hey, you're not going anywhere.
都是因为你 不然我们也不只有两个月的期限
We only have two months to deliver this to the Air Force
然后上交给国家
because of you.
我知道 我当时也在
I know, I was there.
那你就给我清醒点!
Well, wake up!
我们要习惯刷夜了
We're gonna put in a lot of late nights.
刷到多晚?
How late?
我怎么知道 半夜吧 或者凌晨一点
Well, I don't know, midnight, 1:00.
凌晨一点?
One o'clock?
我又不是夜猫子
I'm not a raccoon.
累了的话就去喝咖啡
If you're tired, have some coffee.
我才不喝咖啡 要喝也是你喝
What? You have some coffee.
我正喝着呢!
I am having coffee!
你这么暴躁就是因为咖啡因!
And look how irritable it's making you!
别吵了!
Guys!
现在吵架一点用都没有
We're not gonna get anything done if we start fighting.
你能不能再忍一忍?
Now, can you please try to soldier through?
好啵
Fine.
我真的坚持不住了
I don't think I can go much longer.
才过去三分半钟! 你清醒点!
It's been three and a half minutes, wake up!
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第十季第3集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 酥酥要阳光
校对: UU要找工作
翻译: 凤梨酥 李小宝Licht
翻译: 秋娘娘 熊熊 言小默
我昨晚做噩梦 梦见我最好的朋友变成了暴君
I had a bad dream that my best friend became a tyrant
逼我熬夜工作
and forced me to stay up all night to work.
我做的梦倒是挺好的 昨天我把你扔上床的时候
Oh, I had a good dream that when I carried you to bed,
故意把你的脑袋撞到了墙上 我还不厚道地笑了
I let your head hit the wall and I laughed.
嗨 早上好
Good morning.
你们在干嘛?
What is this?
昨天一晚上都没看到你们
Well, we didn't see you last night,
今天估计也一样
we're not gonna see you today,
所以我们应该一起吃个早饭
so we thought we could have breakfast together.
你们太贤惠了
Oh, that is so nice.
嗷 头很疼的!
Ow, it does hurt!
那你们今天准备干点什么?
So, what are you guys gonna do today?
今天下午Sheldon本来应该
Well, Sheldon was supposed to go
陪我去参加聚会的
to this party with me this afternoon,
不过现在看来他是去不了啦
but I don't think that's happening.
本来我就没打算去
Oh, that was never happening.
带我去吧
Oh, I'll go.
我超喜欢聚会
I like a party.
我们说的这个不是你想象中那种趴体
Well, to be honest, it's not like a "party" party,
更像是不同领域的科学家们
it's more like a gathering
聚在一起讨论他们的工作
where scientists of different disciplines get together
再了解一下其他领域的
to share their work and keep current
最新科研进展
on what's going on in other fields.
我不应该说这是个聚会的 我的锅
I don't know why I called it a party, sorry.
无所谓啦 带我去吧
It's okay, I'll still go.
你不会觉得无聊嘛?
You don't think you'll be bored?
一边喝酒 一边装作在听人们说
Oh, I'll have some wine and listen to people go on
我听不懂的东西
about crap I don't understand.
讲真 这和我每天的工作
I mean, how is it any different
有什么区别吗?
than every single day of my life?
我不去
I won't be there.
他不去的话 那这就真是个聚会了
Look at that, it is a party.
对不起 我整个周末都要加班
Sorry I have to work all weekend.
没事哒
It's okay.
谢谢你给我做早餐
Thanks again for breakfast.
我一晚上都没见到你
Well, I didn't get to see you last night.
我能做的也就只有这些了
It was the least I could do.
你不应该把大门密码设成他生日的
You shouldn't have made the alarm code his birthday.
我们今天干什么?
So, what should we do today?
多谢你啦
Oh, I appreciate it,
不过你不用一整天都陪着我的
but you don't have to spend your day off with me.
没关系啊
Well, I don't mind.
对了 你想不想去商场看看婴儿用品?
Oh, you want go to the mall and look at baby stuff?
不是很想
Not really.
来嘛 我们可以分一个椒盐饼干
Oh, come on, we could share a pretzel
感受一下路边保守的老奶奶歧视我们的眼神
and get sideways glances from racist old ladies.
圣诞节带Howard去见我奶奶的时候
I get enough of that when I take Howard
我就受够那种眼神了
to my grandmother's for Christmas.
Howard是犹太人
唔
Oh,
对了 不如我们开始收拾婴儿房吧?
I know, why don't we get started on clearing out the baby's room?
现在就开始会不会太早了?
Isn't it a little early for that?
终究还是要做的
You have to get to it eventually.
那里堆满了各种垃圾 真是不好意思
Oh, there's so much junk in there, it's embarrassing.
我在旁边的时候你怎么能觉得不好意思呢?
How can you be embarrassed around me?
你生孩子的时候我可是要在你旁边帮你喊加油的
I'm gonna be in the room with you when you give birth.
我并不这么认为
I don't think you are.
你之前还觉得我今天早上不会出现在厨房里呢
You didn't think I was gonna be in your kitchen this morning,
看看现在
yet here I am.
嗨 大宝贝
Psst, hey, kid.
什么?
Huh, what?
你看上去累惨了
You look tired.
来点功能饮料怎么样?
Why don't you have an energy drink?
大家都喝的
Everyone's doing it.
不了 谢谢你 这种饮料里有咖啡因
Oh, no, thank you, those have caffeine in them.
噢 不好意思
Oh, sorry,
我以为你很酷
I thought you were cool.
宝宝确实酷
I am cool.
这是Yoo-hoo
This is Yoo-hoo,
好喝的淡味版巧克力牛奶
chocolate milk's delicious watery cousin.
好吧
All right.
但如果你想体会拥有超能力的感觉的话
But if you ever want to feel like you have superpowers,
就试试这个吧
try one of these.
超级英雄通过摄入化学物质来增强能力?
Superheroes take performance-enhancing chemicals?
不然呢
You bet.
你知道绿巨人为什么那么壮吗?
You know why Hulk is so strong?
来点类固醇就行
Steroids.
你知道为什么蝙蝠侠大半夜在外面乱晃
You know why Batman wanders around at night
还打架吗?
getting into fights?
全是威士忌的功劳
Scotch.
我现在有巨量的工作要做
I am facing a great deal of work.
而且我确实更偏爱名人喜欢的东西
And I do like things better when famous people also like them.
给你
Here.
我请
It's on the house.
第一罐还免费?
The first one's free?
闪电侠 你是怎么赚钱的?
Flash, how do you stay in business?
想知道我的秘诀吗?
You want to know my secret?
我买了漫威的股票
I bought stock in Marvel.
嗨 Bert
Hi, Bert.
这是我的朋友 Penny
This is my friend, Penny.
你好
Hi.
嘿 进来吧
Hey, come on in.
我去放点摇滚乐
I'll gonna go turn on some rock music.
rock又可以译作石头
这是个地质学的笑话
That's a geology joke.
Bert是个地质学家
Bert's a geologist.
还是搞笑小能手哦
And a joker.
我们是来得有多早?
How early are we?
实际上我们已经迟到一小时了
Oh, actually, we're an hour late.
突然好希望Sheldon在这里啊
I suddenly wish Sheldon was here.
我都不知道从哪里下手
I don't even know where to begin.
在音乐之声里 Julie Andrews说过
Well, in The Sound of Music, Julie Andrews says,
我们从头唱起
"Let's start at the very beginning.
这样最是好记
A very good place to start."
我本来还打算从结尾处开始呢
Oh, I was gonna start at the end.
真是谢谢你在这里啊
Thank God you're here.
首先要丢掉的东西就是你充满恶意的语气
Well, I think the first thing we should get rid of is that tone.
抱歉
Sorry.
还是把这个留着吧
I should probably keep this
万一是个女儿
in case we have a girl.
挺不错的小房子啊
Oh, that's a nice one.
是你小时候的玩具?
Was it yours when you were little?
是我爸爸给我造的
My dad built it for me.
哇 真暖心啊
Wow, it's so cute.
这是丈夫 这是妻子
This was the husband and this was the wife.
他们一起外出历险
They'd go out on adventures together.
航海 滑雪
Cruises, skiing,
骑马
horseback riding.
也就是我把他们用胶带绑在狗身上
That was really me just duct taping them to our dog.
那他们有孩子吗?
Oh, and did they have kids?
有啊 但是为人父母 他们一点都不喜欢自己的孩子
They did, but the mommy and daddy didn't like them,
所以他们把孩子送去了孤儿院
so they shipped them off to an orphanage
我用鞋盒做的
I made out of a shoebox.
你这么说还真是让人"放心"啊
Yeah, that's not worrisome at all.
不是每个女孩都梦想着为人母的一天
Not every girl dreams about being a mom.
有的时候你觉得自己这辈子都不会要孩子
Sometimes you think you're never gonna have kids
但某一天你睁开眼睛就发现自己怀孕了
and one day you wake up and you're pregnant.
不管你的职业生涯现在是多么璀璨
And it doesn't matter that your career's going great right now
甚至你和你的老公以后那都不能去
and that you and your husband never even got to go anywhere
被这狗孩子绑得死死的!
taped to a dog!
我居然因为这个翘了动感单车课
I skipped spin class for this.
为什么他去自动贩卖机
Why is it taking him so long
买个饮料要花这么久?
to get a drink out of a vending machine?
这个说来就话长了
Oh, it's complicated.
他觉得推开取物口的小门
He finds pushing that little door
把手伸进机器里的这个行为已经亲密得让他不舒服了
and reaching up into the machine uncomfortably intimate.
众爱卿 朕准备好开始工作了
Gentlemen, I am ready to work.
引用火星救援的一句话 "我们好好科学一把"
To quote The Martian, "Let's science the feces out of this!"
我说的是那本书
That's The Martian the book
和电影 不是火星人马文
and The Martian the movie, not Marvin the Martian.
再引用火星人马文的一句话
Although to quote Marvin the Martian,
"我将此星球
"I claim this planet
命名为火星"
in the name of Mars."
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
哦 我感觉好极了 简直不能更赞
Oh, I'm fantastic, never been better.
我刚刚第一次喝了功能性饮料
I had my first energy drink
啊感觉棒棒哒
and I feel great.
嘿 你们想摔跤玩吗?
Hey, you guys want to wrestle?
我们可以掰腕子 拇指摔跤 泥浆摔跤 相扑摔跤
We can do arm, thumb, mud, sumo.
还是算了吧 我们不够胖 也没穿尿不湿
Nah, we're not fat enough, or wearing diapers.
这可是你说想让他清醒过来的
You wanted him awake.
我们是应该两个人说说话呢 还是应该去和大家聊天啊?
So should we talk to each other or mingle?
我不知道大家都去哪儿了
I don't know where everyone is.
嗯 我看
Yeah, I mean,
他这个体型吃掉一两个客人还是有可能的
I could see him eating one or two guests,
但是吃掉一整个派对的人还是差一点
but not a whole party.
诶 这个派对太糗了
Well, I guess this is kind of a bust.
你们不用接着等了
You don't have to stay.
我要开始打扫卫生了
I'm gonna start cleaning up.
好吧
Okay.
留他一个人在这儿我好内疚啊
I feel so bad about leaving him here.
哦哈哈 我刚刚也在想要是扔下你走了会怎么样
Oh, it's funny, I was just thinking the same thing about you.
恩 听我说
Hey, listen,
你可不可以不和大学里的人
could you not say anything about this
说今天的事啊?
to the people at the university?
你知道的 因为...
You know, 'cause...
你是你啊 我就只是我 真是太丢人了
you're you and I'm me, and it's kind of embarrassing.
等一下 你刚刚说“你是你啊”是什么意思?
Wait, what do you mean "she's her"?
就是 你知道Amy是校区里最酷的女孩吧?
Well, you know how Amy's the coolest girl on campus, right?
- 不知道 - 不知道啊
- No. - No.
没错啊 大家都是这么想的
Oh yeah, everybody thinks so.
什么?
What?
你得了脚气都告诉我 但是这件事你跟我保密?
You tell me about your foot fungus, but this is a secret?
大概是因为我和Sheldon在一起吧
I'm sure it's just 'cause I'm dating Sheldon.
恩 其实 我觉得Sheldon是因为和你在一起 他才这么受欢迎的
Mm, actually, I think Sheldon's popular because he's dating you.
Sheldon什么时候受欢迎了?
Now Sheldon's popular?
什么情况啊?
What is happening?
要不我们休息下去吃午饭吧
Maybe we should break for lunch.
现在几点了?
What time is it?
根据世界上最差劲的布谷鸟钟 现在两点了
According to the world's worst cuckoo clock, it's 2:00.
我头好疼啊
My head hurts
而且我从来没这么累过
and I'm more tired than ever.
要不你还是回家吧?
Why don't you just go home?
不不 我可以的
No, I can do this.
我只是 只是需要再来一瓶功能性饮料
I just, I just need another energy drink.
哦 不要啊
Oh, no.
怎么了?
What?
我还想再喝一瓶
I want another one.
那怎么了?
So?
这是药物渴求
That's a craving.
是药物依赖的表现啊
That's a sign of chemical dependency.
你只喝了一瓶啊
You only had one.
哎 我知道
No, I know,
但是很多东西都是
but plenty of things are addictive
试了一次就上瘾了
after a single exposure.
比如说 可卡因 尼古丁 还有品客薯片
I mean, crack cocaine, nicotine, Pringles.
只要打开了一桶 不吃完简直停不下来
You know once one pops one just can't stop.
药物依赖是不会这么快开始的
You can't develop a problem that fast.
我们打赌啊? 哦 好吧
You want to bet? Oh, great,
我还开始赌博上瘾了
now I'm addicted to gambling.
我们不能再这么浪费时间了
We can't afford to lose any more time.
虽然说估计没什么用 但是有人试过
Well, this probably won't work, but has anyone ever tried
暴打他一顿把他打正常吗?
to just haul off and whoop the crazy out of him?
这个建议一点用都没有好嘛
That's not helpful.
想想觉得好有意思 但是还是一点用都没有啊
It's fun to think about, but it's not helpful.
嘿 Sheldon 我们时间紧任务重
Hey, Sheldon, we are on a serious time crunch.
没有你我们绝对做不完的
We can't do this without you.
你能不能振作起来啊?
Can you please pull it together?
对不起 嗯 我一定
I'm sorry. Yes, of course.
谢谢
Thank you.
不过 如果我出现咖啡因戒断反应
Just, please, bear with me if I display symptoms
你们一定要包容我
of caffeine withdrawal.
没问题
No worries.
你们两个该洗澡了
You guys stink.
真对不起我刚才跟你发脾气了
Sorry I flipped out on you.
大概是荷尔蒙在作怪吧
I think it's just hormones.
你怀孕之前就很刻薄
I think you were mean before you were pregnant,
但是没事我不介意
but it's fine.
所以说 如果我们不收拾房间的话
So, uh, instead of cleaning out the room,
要不我们给婴儿房选一个主题吧?
why don't we just decide on a theme for the nursery?
婴儿房真的需要有一个主题吗?
Does it really need one?
当然需要啦
Of course it does.
你小时候的房间没有主题吗?
Didn't your baby room have a theme?
恩 我小时候的房间也是我爸爸的办公室
Well, it doubled as my dad's office,
他是个警察 所以我猜
and he was a cop, so I guess the theme was
主题就是血淋淋的谋杀现场照片
bloody homicide photos.
哦 我的房间是小熊维尼主题的
Oh. Mine was Winnie the Pooh.
但是...
But anyway...
要不我们先不用着急
why don't we just take a step back
先选定一个颜色怎么样?
and start with a color?
你看怎么样? 有很多漂亮的颜色啊
Right? There are so many amazing ones.
红色 蓝色 绿色 紫色...
Red, blue, green, purple...
你是想要念出全世界的颜色吗?
Are you just gonna name all the colors?
呃 你说话之后就不想了
Well, not now.
我一点都不关心婴儿房是什么颜色的
I don't care what color the room is.
好吧 嗯 我只是想帮帮你
Okay, well, I'm just trying to help you.
然而 你在帮倒忙 别说了!
Well, you're not, so just drop it!
我显然很生气 你为什么不追过来?
I'm clearly upset. Why aren't you following me?
对不起! 对不起!
Sorry! Sorry!
当Amy开始用铬酸
And when Amy started using a solution of chromic acid
和白醋清洗她的设备之后
and white vinegar to clean all her lab equipment,
突然 所有人都开始这么做了
all of a sudden, everybody was doing it.
你引领了时尚潮流哈!
You trend setter!
只是在对的时机有了对的主意
Just the right idea at the right time.
好的 好的 所以Amy很棒 Sheldon很棒
Okay, okay, so Amy's cool, Sheldon's cool.
给我讲讲Leonard 谁?
Tell me about Leonard. Who?
就是Leonard Hofstadter
Leonard Hofstadter.
哦 他呀 我觉得他挺好的
Oh, him. I guess he's all right.
显然他哄骗了一个很性感的姑娘嫁给他
Apparently he tricked some hot girl into marrying him.
那是我 我就是那个姑娘
That's me, I'm her.
他没有骗我
You know, he didn't trick me.
他只是追的我都累了
He just wore me down.
你俩确实应该是好朋友
It makes sense you two are friends.
性感的姑娘总是一起玩
I mean, hot girls always stick together.
你还说这不会是一个
And you thought this wasn't gonna be
好派对呢
a great party.
我都不知道
You know, I had no idea
加州理工跟我的高中这么像
Caltech is exactly like my high school.
嗯 并不是完全相似
Well, it's not exactly like it.
我们加州理工的人都十分聪明
We're all extremely smart.
哇哦... 你们这些受欢迎的姑娘这么高冷
Wow... you popular girls are mean.
我去拿点咖啡 你想要么?
I'm gonna get some coffee. You want some?
啊 你真的要在我面前摄入咖啡因
Uh, you're really going to have caffeine in front of me
就在我的生活要步入正轨的时候?
when I'm trying to get my life back on track?
啊 好吧 我们假装你确实有毛病
Uh, okay, let's pretend you do have a problem.
- 我确实有  - 你没有
- I do.  - You don't.
- 不 我有  - 不 你没有!
- Yeah, but I do.  - No, you don't!
但是我们假设你有
But let's say you do.
不要说你有 因为你没有!
And don't say you do, because you don't!
现在 你不觉得把自己投入到
Now, wouldn't you think that throwing yourself
工作中是解决它的最好办法么?
into your work would be the best way to deal with it?
解决什么? 你的毛病
With what? Your problem.
你不是说我没毛病
I thought I didn't have a problem.
看得我都尴尬了
That was painful to watch.
所以我们要去哪?
So where are we going?
我不知道
I don't know.
好吧
Okay.
我们像一对末路狂花
How Thelma and Louise of us.
Raj 我为什么什么都不在意呢?
Raj, why don't I care about anything?
什么?
I'm sorry?
这是我的孩子
It's my baby.
我该关心婴儿房和颜色
I should care about nurseries and colors,
但是我并不关心 我这是怎么了?
and I don't... what's wrong with me?
可能跟你小时候看的那些犯罪现场照片有关吧
Well, crime-scene photos near your crib spring to mind.
我一直期待着开始感到兴奋
I keep waiting to feel excited,
但是我并没有
but it's not happening.
如果我永远都不兴奋怎么办?
What if it never happens?
Bernafdette 放松点 看
Bernadette, come on, look,
你想的太多了 好么?
you're overthinking this, okay?
你会成为一个棒极了的母亲
You're gonna be an amazing mom.
即使你不相信
Even if you don't believe it,
我知道你有母性的本能
I know you have maternal instincts.
有一次 我照顾我的弟弟们
Once, I was supposed to babysit my brothers.
我们的邻居发现他们没穿衣服在后院里
Our neighbor found them naked in the backyard
吃蟋蟀
eating crickets.
快乐而且吃得很饱
Happy and well-fed.
你看 这是我从这个故事里获取的信息
You see, that's what I'm taking from that story.
Leonard 我能问你个问题么
Leonard, can I ask you a question?
是你本该搞得定的
Is it about the rotational symmetries
旋转对称的问题
you should be figuring out
还是你的伪咖啡因问题?
or your fake caffeine problem?
Howard 我能问你个问题么?
Howard, can I ask you a question?
不能
No.
好吧 那我就直接说了
All right, I'll just toss this out to the room.
嗯 我在想
Um, I was thinking that the best way
对抗我的依赖性的最好方法
to fight my addiction is by
是让我逐步戒掉
weaning myself off in steps.
我找不到咖啡因贴片
Now, I couldn't find a caffeine patch,
但是我找到了一个
but I did find what claims to be
促进思考的咖啡因栓剂
a mind-boosting caffeine suppository.
好
Yeah.
你知道 关于直肠有个有趣的事实...
You know, the interesting fact about the rectum...
Sheldon啊!
Sheldon!
因为你 我们才有了空军给的
We are dealing with an impossible deadline
根本不可能完成的期限
from the Air Force because of you.
所以喝功能性饮料 不喝功能性饮料
So have an energy drink, don't have an energy drink.
用栓剂给你捅进去
Order suppositories and shove 'em
捅哪里 我都不在意!
wherever you want, I don't care!
不是捅的
You don't shove them.
它自带一个方便滑入的工具
They come with an easy-glide applicator.
好的 听我说
Right. Listen to me.
你把活干完之前我们什么都干不了
We can't do anything until you do your part.
所以快起来到白板前把活干完!
So get up in front of this whiteboard and do it!
我不能 不 你可以
I can't. Yes, you can.
不...
No...
我解不出来这数学
I can't figure out the math.
我努力了很多天了
I've been racking my brain for days,
可是我想不出来
and I've got nothing.
你讲真的吗?
Seriously?
我做不到
I can't do it.
我没我以为的那么聪明
I'm not as smart as I think I am.
我太抱歉了 这都是我的错
I'm so sorry. This is all my fault.
没关系的 我们总会有办法的
It's okay, we'll figure something out.
但要是我们就是没法子怎么办啊?
But what if we can't?
会没事的 你总会想通的
It'll be fine. You'll see.
喂Sheldon?
Sheldon?
伙计?
Buddy?
等孩子生出来了
When the baby gets here,
你得把这招教我
you gotta teach me that.
太感谢你了 Bert 今天太棒了
Thank you so much, Bert. This was great.
我的荣幸
My pleasure.
你们妹子想带盆
You girls want to take home
两加仑的土豆色拉回家吗?
a two-gallon tub of potato salad?
还是不用了吧 咱们
I think we're good.
好吧 感谢你们能来
Okay, well, thanks for coming by.
你们都是好人啊
You're nice people.
你也是啊 说真的
Well, so are you. In fact, you know what?
我们永远不会把你的好意当作想当岩的
We will never take you for granite.
听出来了吗? 花岗岩 想当岩?
Did you get that? Granite?
一点地质小玩笑啦
A little geology joke.
你们得走了
You need to leave.
我已经爱上你们两个人了
I'm in love with both of you now.
好吧 拜
Okay. Bye.
呃 停车
Uh, pull over.
什么? 为什么? 你在给谁打电话啊?
What? Why? Who are you calling?
你要跟Howard打我的小报告了 是不是?
You're gonna rat me out to Howard, aren't you?
你真是个告密的小婊砸 怪不得我不喜欢你呢
You're such a snitch, no wonder I don't like you.
喂喂 我是在跟我爸打电话 好吗?
Whoa, I'm calling my dad, okay?
他有跟怀孕的女士相处的经验
He's got experience dealing with pregnant ladies
因为他是妇科医生
because he's an OBGYN.
也有跟蛇精病女士的相处经验
And experience with crazy ladies
因为他娶了我妈
because of my mom.
哈喽 Rajesh
Hello, Rajesh.
你是打电话来要钱的吗?
Are you calling to ask for money?
什么? 不
What? No.
那你是打电话来要
Are you calling to ask for things
- 需要花钱的东西的吗?  - 不是的
- that cost money?  - No.
太好了 什么事?
Great. What's up?
这是我朋友 Bernadette
This is my friend, Bernadette.
她怀孕了 然后她有点担心
She's pregnant, and she's a bit worried,
所以我觉得说不定你能跟她谈谈
so I thought maybe you could talk to her.
当然 你有什么担心的呢?
Of course. What seems to be the trouble?
就是感觉不对劲
Something's wrong.
我一点也不在乎那些所有其他妈妈
I don't care about any of the baby stuff
都特别感兴趣的有关小宝宝的东西
every other mom is so into.
说实话 我都不确定我喜欢小宝宝
Honestly, I'm not even sure I like babies.
听着 有些人天生就是喜欢小宝宝的
Look, some people are baby people,
而有些人天生就跟不爱跟小宝宝那么亲热
and some people are not baby people.
但这并不代表你不爱你自己的宝宝
It doesn't mean you won't love your own baby.
但是我以为我会更兴奋的
But I thought I'd be more excited.
哎呀 兴奋也什么都保证不了啊
Oh, being excited isn't a guarantee of anything.
Rajesh的妈妈怀他的时候可兴奋了
Rajesh's mother was thrilled when she was pregnant with him.
他生出来以后做什么事 他妈妈都宠着他
After he was born, she doted on his every move.
但你知道后来怎么了吗?
And you know what happened?
他深深地伤了他妈妈的心 跑到了半个世界之外
He broke her heart, moved halfway around the world,
还只跟穷鬼白人女谈恋爱
and dates only poor white women.
所以啦 你永远不知道会发生什么嘛
So you never know.
谢谢 我现在感觉好多了
Thank you. I feel better now.
- 可我感觉不好啊!  - 很好
- I don't!  - Good.
Bernadette 我希望你生个女儿
Bernadette, I hope you have a daughter.
唉 我也不知道这该怎么说
Um, I don't really know how to say this.
你可以从叫我"长官"开始说起
Well, you could try starting with "sir".
哦对 对不起 长官
Right. Sorry, sir.
他说从长官说起 不是以长官结尾
He said start with it, not end with it.
- 长官...  - 嗯?
- Sir... - Hmm?
我们现在碰了点小钉子
We've hit a bit of a snag.
我们已经落后进度了
We're already behind schedule.
解决军用问题所需要的
The computations required to overcome
计算量
the deployability issues
比我们想象的要大很多
are more significant than we thought.
我知道我们签了合同
I understand that we're under contract,
然后我也不是很清楚违反合同
and I don't know what the consequences
的后果是什么 但是...
of violating that are, but, uh...
我们在约定期限内
we're not gonna be able to deliver
是没法给出成果了
in the time we promised.
那你们需要多久呢?
How long do you need?
我们... 我们觉得... 两年
We... we're thinking... two years.
好吧
All right.
就这样吗?
That's it?
你对此没意见吗?
You're okay with that?
你们以为你们是头一个不守时的
You think you're the first government contractor
政府合约者么?
who isn't gonna deliver on time?
我们现在还在等着里根总统下令制造的
We're still waiting for a big space laser
大型宇宙激光枪用来打败共产那帮人呢
Reagan ordered to beat the commies.
感谢你的理解 长官
Thanks for understanding, sir.
是啊 太感谢你了
Yes, thank you so much.
我们... 我们真的很感谢你的理解
We... we really appreciate it.
好吧 没压力了
All right, pressure's off
看电影么?
Wanna see a movie?
爆米花我请
Popcorn's on me.